Steven Ford Brown Heart's Invention: On the Poetry of Vassar Miller Papers, 1982-1987
University of Houston Libraries
Steven Ford Brown Heart's Invention: On the Poetry of Vassar Miller Papers
1982-1987
Brown, Steven Ford
1987-001
1 box; .4 linear feet
In 1988, Heart's Invention: On the Poetry of Vassar Miller was published as volume 5 in the American Poets Profile Series by Ford-Brown & Co. The collection consists of materials related to the publication of the book, including correspondence, typescript drafts, and galley proofs.
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Biographical Note
In 1988, Heart's Invention: On the Poetry of Vassar Miller was published as volume 5 in the American Poets Profile Series by Ford-Brown & Co. Heart’s Invention was the first book-length critical study to focus on the work of Texas poet Vassar Miller, and included a preface from novelist Larry McMurtry. The book was edited by Steven Ford Brown.
Steven Ford Brown is a prolific editor and translator. His recent books include Astonishing World: The Selected Poems of Angel Gonzalez, 1956-1986 (as editor and translator) and Invited Guest: An Anthology of Twentieth-Century Southern Poetry (as co-editor). Originally from Alabama, and a resident of Houston, Texas for five years, Brown currently lives in Boston, Massachusetts.
Scope and Contents
The Steven Ford Brown Heart's Invention: On the Poetry of Vassar Miller Papers consist of materials related to the publication of the book. This includes correspondence, typescript drafts, and galley proofs.
Subjects (Persons)
Miller, Vassar; Brown, Steven Ford; McMurtry, Larry
Subjects
Miller, Vassar -- Criticism and interpretation
Titles
xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="">Heart's Invention-- archives.
Formats
Correspondence; Typescript drafts; Galley Proofs
Access Restrictions
Open for research.
Acquisition Information
This collection was donated by Steven Ford Brown in 1987.
Detailed Description
  - Correspondence: Steven Ford Brown, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Robert Bonazzi, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Robert Bonazzi, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: B-K, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: L-Q, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Q-Z, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Cassette tape from Sister Bernetta Quinn, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Typescript draft, corrected (photocopy), 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8-13)
  - Notes and bibliography drafts, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Typescript draft, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Galley proofs, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16-18)
  - Page proofs, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Publication materials, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Articles about Vassar Miller, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1980s] (Box 1, Folder 22)